gadball.com 2010-05-15

# Privacy Statement | Build a profile, search jobs, career tools for job seekers by GadBall

**Effective October 1, 2009:**

## About GadBall.com

GadBall is an online professional, personal and career community networking service. Users of the GadBall website and service ("Users") can post personal information to create a Profile on the GadBall website. Once a Profile on GadBall is created, Users have access to numerous features of the GadBall site. As a GadBall User who has created a Profile on this website, you have provided us with your personal information. This document describes how GadBall will use and protect the personal information of our Users.

The privacy of our Users is extremely important to GadBall. The personal information shared with us by our Users is only used to enhance the service we provide to our Users. The personal information of our Users will be used anonymously to determine advertisements displayed to our Users, however, NEVER will GadBall transmit any User information to any third party, or advertiser, without the EXPLICIT authorization of our User.

Third party advertisements are displayed to our Users on the GadBall website based on the personal information provided to us by the User. When a third party advertiser on the GadBall website requires personal information (e.g. contact information) which the User had previously saved on the GadBall website, GadBall will attempt to pre-fill the advertiser's information request fields with the GadBall User's personal information - BUT THIS IS ONLY TO ELIMINATE the need to re-input the data by our User. In EVERY case, the User MUST validate the pre-filled information and manually and personally submit the User's personal information to the third party. GadBall will NEVER provide a GadBall User's personal information to a third party.

Several features of GadBall provide the opportunity for Users to receive email notifications from GadBall. To receive these communications from GadBall, the User must personally opt-in, and the opt-in screens will clearly state what emails the User can expect to receive from GadBall. In EVERY case where a User receives an email communication from GadBall, the email from GadBall includes a method (usually an unsubscribe link) permitting the User to change or delete the preferences which prompted the email. Our commitment to our Users is that we will immediately update our email systems to support the intent of our Users.

Periodically, GadBall will need to contact our Users via email communication regarding the service. We will NOT include advertisements from third parties in our email communications to our Users, and each email communication from GadBall will provide our Users with a link to permanently remove the User from future email notifications.

One of the Features of GadBall is integration with third party job boards and social networks. This integration is achieved through direct advertising on the GadBall site, or links to other sites. To facilitate the transfer of data, GadBall may pre-fill information request forms from advertisers (as described above) or provide the User a browser Add-On to host the User's data as the User accesses other internet websites. In each case User data from GadBall can be used to pre-fill data fields on these websites, but the User will personally and manually decide to submit the information to any of these sites. In the event a User opts-in for a service where the User's information is automatically submitted to a third party on behalf of the User, the User will decide what personal information is transmitted and which third party websites will receive the User's personal information.

Users can also create personal Profiles and link these to other Users through User established networks. When a User elects to participate in the Networking features of GadBall, the User, not GadBall, controls which personal information is shared with other Users of GadBall.

GadBall Users can view the Public Profiles of other Users, communicate with friends (both new and old) on the service, share photos, post messages and comments, and describe their professional, personal, and career interests. To enrich and facilitate the experiences of our Users we request and display some personal information to other Users and visitors of GadBall, which allows Users to identify each other and expand their networks; the information displayed by GadBall is the Public Profile information presented by the User. GadBall Users can edit their Profile information, and change the status from / to Public or Private at any time.

A Note to Our Users: Public Profiles are formatted by GadBall so that they are indexed by search engines; this is a service to our Users. It is important for our Users to understand that there are websites on the internet that store every internet web page. What this means is that each User should personally review the Profile BEFORE making it Public. 

## Information Collection and Use by GadBall.com

GadBall collects personal informatioun submitted by our Users. This information includes Profile data explicitly provided to GadBall by Users, as well as demographic and site utilization data to authenticate Users and to send notifications to Users relating to the GadBall service. GadBall also collects other profile data including but not limited to: personal interests, gender, age, work history, education and occupation in order to assist Users in finding and communicating with each other and customize the User experience (including advertising by third parties) on our site.

GadBall logs non-personally identifiable information including IP address, aggregate profile information, aggregate User data, aggregate Profile content, and browser type, from Users and visitors to the site. User IP addresses are recorded for security and monitoring purposes. All of this data is used to manage the website, track usage, display relevant advertising, and improve the website services. This non-personally identifiable information may be shared with third-parties to facilitate the provision of more relevant services and advertisements to members.

GadBall will never provide, share, rent or sell User-specific personal information to any third parties, unless the User requests GadBall to transmit this information on the User's behalf - and in EVERY case the User must personally and manually elect to participate in this information transfer.

User Public Profile information, when the User's profile is set to "Public", is displayed to other Users, visitors to the site, and formatted such that the User's Profile is publicly accessible by third party search engines and the entire internet.

Email addresses are used for the purposes of inviting new friends to join GadBall, to add Users to a User's friends' network(s), and to send notifications related to the service. With the exception of inviting friends, adding friends, and notifications, a User's eMail address is not shared or displayed to people within a User's personal network. Users within a personal network communicate on GadBall with each other through the GadBall service, without disclosing their email addresses. Users' full names are never directly revealed to other members. To facilitate searching and finding friends and acquaintances on the service, GadBall allows Users to search for other Public Profiles using first and last name, email address, words, terms and contextual content of the Profile, and schools and/or companies where Users may have attended or worked.

Email addresses of non-GadBall Users provided by Users for GadBall Features (such as Profile Recommendations, Reviews, and Proof-Reading) are utilized by GadBall solely to initiate, coordinate, facilitate, and complete the User experience for which the email address was provided to GadBall.

GadBall may also use a User's personal email address to send updates, notifications of unread email messages, or a newsletter or news regarding the service. Users may choose not to receive email of this type by changing their "notification" settings on the User "Account Settings". In every case, any email communication by GadBall will include a provision to opt-out of future email communications.

GadBall or a partner may sponsor a promotion, sweepstake or contest on GadBall. Participating Users may be asked to provide personal information including (but not limited to) name, email address or home address or to answer questions in order to participate. GadBall will make it clear at the point of collection who is collecting the personal information; the User electing transfer of information from GadBall is responsible for reviewing the Privacy Policy of the recipient – this includes the resume distribution service of GadBall in which the User specifically selects the sites to receive the User's resume.

## Invitations and Other Communications to Non-members GadBall

Users can invite friends to particpate in or join the service by sending emails via our automated system. GadBall stores the email addresses that Users provide so that the respondents may be added to the User's network, and to send the request, and also to send reminders of the requests. GadBall does not sell, rent, or trade these email addresses or use them to send any other communication besides requests and request reminders (up to three [3] per email address). Recipients of invitations from GadBall may contact GadBall to request the removal of their information from our database; each email message will include a provision to permit the recipient to opt-out of receiving future email communications from GadBall.

GadBall Users may also store email addresses and other contact information of people they know in their internal GadBall account and may also choose to send invitations and other communications to those addresses. 

## Use of Cookies

GadBall uses cookies to store User and Visitor preferences and to record session information, for enhancement of the User experience (including ensuring that visitors are not repeatedly offered the same advertisements) and to customize newsletter, advertising, and Web page content based on browser type and User information. Users may be able to configure their browser to accept or reject all or some cookies, or notify the User when a cookie is set. Each browser is different; it is the User's responsibility to check the "Help" menu of the User's browser to learn how to change cookie preferences. However, you must enable cookies from GadBall in order to use most functions on the site. Users Please Note: GadBall allows 3rd party advertisers that are presenting advertisements on some of our pages to set and access their cookies on your computer; this is a common internet practice. Each advertiser's use of cookies is subject to their own privacy policies, not the GadBall Privacy Policy. 

## Links

GadBall contains links to sites. GadBall.com is not responsible for the privacy policies and/or practices on other sites. When linking to another site each User should read the privacy policy stated on that site. Our privacy policy only governs information collected on GadBall. 

## Chat Rooms, Discussion Forums, Journals and WebLogs, Message Boards, Classifieds and Public Forums

All Users, please be aware that whenever you voluntarily post public information to any page on GadBall, that the information you post can be accessed by the public and can in turn be used by those people to send you unsolicited communications. For this reason we recommend that Users only post their resumes to third party employment sites using the GadBall service and Users refrain from posting contact information of any type on any internet website(s). 

## Correcting/Updating or Removing Information

GadBall Users may modify or remove any of their personal information at any time by logging into their account, accessing the appropriate features, and making the desired changes. 

## Email Choice/Opt-out

GadBall Users who no longer wish to receive notifications may choose not to by logging into their account, accessing the appropriate features, and making the desired changes. All notification emails from GadBall also include the above instructions for opting-out of those communications in the future. 

## Third Party Advertising

Ads appearing on this Web site may be delivered to Users by GadBall or one of our Web advertising partners. Our Web advertising partners may set cookies. These cookies allow the ad server to recognize your computer each time they send you an online advertisement. In this way, ad servers may compile information about where you, or others who are using your computer, saw their advertisements and determine which ads are clicked on. This information allows an ad network to deliver targeted advertisements that they believe will be of most interest to you. This privacy statement covers the use of cookies by GadBall and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers. 

## Security

GadBall User accounts are secured by member-created UserID's and Passwords. GadBall takes precautions to insure that User account information is kept private. We use reasonable measures to protect User information that is stored within our database, and we restrict access to User information to those employees who need access to perform their job functions, such as our technical staff. Please note that no company, including GadBall, can guarantee the security of User account information. Users will note that on GadBall we do NOT collect personally identifiable information such as social security numbers, credit card numbers, or bank account information. Users must personally research any third party advertisers who do require this information, and even if the request for this information appears to be on the GadBall Site, the User is required to research the advertiser; Users, not GadBall, GadBall's Parent Company, or any of GadBall's subsidiaries, are responsible for transmitting any personally identifiable information to third parties, even if such third party was found by the User by accessing the GadBall site.

Unauthorized entry or use, hardware or software failure, and other factors may compromise the security of User information at any time. GadBall recognizes the trust of our Users is the foundation for our long-term success; we review our security processes regularly, and we attempt to take every commercially reasonable step to keep our systems updated with the newest in security technologies to protect our Users' information. 

## Sharing and Disclosure of Information

Except as described above, GadBall will not disclose personal information to any third party without a User's explicit permission unless required by law. GadBall reserves the right to transfer personal information to a successor in interest that acquires rights to that information as a result of the sale of GadBall. For more information see the "Changes in Our Privacy Policy" section below. 

## Changes in Our Privacy Policy

From time to time we may make changes to our privacy policy. If we make changes, we will post them on our site to make Users aware of what the changes are so Users will always be aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and when we may disclose it. A User is bound by any minor changes to the policy when she or he uses the site after those changes have been posted. If, however, we are going to use Users' personally identifiable information in a manner materially different from that stated at the time of collection we will notify Users by posting a notice on our Web site for 30 days. 

## Contacting the Web Site

Upholding the privacy of our Users is paramount to GadBall. If you have any questions concerning this privacy policy, please contact us. If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this Web site, please contact us (Privacy Administrator, GadBall.com, 1400 Quail Street, Suite 260, Newport Beach, CA 92660).

Thank you for your interest in how we address Privacy for our Users; we hope you are comfortable joining us and that you benefit from the service(s) we provide – Welcome to GadBall!
